Association of Canadian Publishers fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Book and Periodical Development Council, 1975 - 1981; F-57-14; 25 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records documenting the ACP's relationship with the Book and Periodical Development Council and as a member of three committees within it. Included are minutes and papers of the Council and General meetings from 1978; the 1978 Book and Periodical Development Council bylaws, memos, reports, briefs and correspondence relating to the first two years of the Council's existence; the results of a 1978 election survey on publishing policies of the three federal political parties and minutes and papers of the Freedom of Information Committee, the Task Force on Library Information and the Distribution Task Force.
  The series has been arranged hierarchically.
  - By-Laws, 1978; F-57-14-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Council - Agenda, Minutes and Papers, 1978; F-57-14-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Council - Agenda, Minutes and Papers, 1979; F-57-14-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Council - Agenda, Minutes and Papers (also Library Information Committee), 1980; F-57-14-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Council - Agenda, Minutes and Papers, 1981; F-57-14-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Council - Agenda, Minutes and Papers, 1981; F-57-14-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - General - Memoranda, Reports, Briefs, Correspondence, 1975 - 1977; F-57-14-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Executive Directors Meetings, 1977 - 1978; F-57-14-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Questionnaire to Political Parties, 1978; F-57-14-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Freedom of Expression Committee - Minutes and Papers, 1978; F-57-14-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 57-102)
  - Freedom of Expression Committee - Minutes and Papers, 1979 - 1981; F-57-14-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Freedom of Expression Committee - Censorship Kit, 1978 - 1979; F-57-14-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Freedom of Expression - Obscenity bill, 1978 - 1979; F-57-14-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Search Committee - Papers, 1977 - 1979; F-57-14-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Distribution Task Force - Minutes and Papers, 1978 - 1979; F-57-14-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Distribution Task Force - Minutes and Papers, 1979 - 1980; F-57-14-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Distribution Task Force - Computerization Questionanaire, 1978 - 1979; F-57-14-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Distribution Task Force - Ingram, Baker and Taylor, 1979; F-57-14-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Distribution Task Force - Teleordering, 1978 - 1979; F-57-14-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Education Task Force - Minutes and Papers, 1978 - 1979; F-57-14-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
  - Library Information Task Force - Minutes and Papers, 1975 - 1980; F-57-14-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 57-103)
- Research and policy files, 1972 - 1985; F-57-15; 87 cm of textual records 3 photographs; Physical description: 3 photographs located in F-57-15-1-3
  Series consists of several groups of working files, most apparently maintained by the IPA/ACP's Executive Directors, and reflecting the Association's efforts in gathering information and monitoring and encouraging government policy on aspects of the book publishing industry. Included are correspondence, minutes, lists, speeches, reports, memoranda, questionnaires, surveys, and statutes.
  - Book Publishing and Public Policy Conference, 1980 - 1981; F-57-15-1; 13 cm of textual records 3 photographs
    Subseries consists of records of the Book Publishing and Public Policy Conference, held in Ottawa in April, 1981, which was sponsored jointly by the ACP and the Writer's Union of Canada. Included are correspondence, minutes and papers of the organizing committee, mailing and registration lists, invitations, programs, photographs, speeches and briefs from the conference's keynote speakers (Francis Fox, Margaret Atwood, Bryan Sims, Roy MacSkimming, James Lorimer and Patsy Aldana), and notes and proceedings from the conference panels.
    - Conference Organization 1/3 - Correspondence and Minutes, 1980; F-57-15-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 57-104)
    - Conference Organization 2/3, 1981; F-57-15-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 57-104)
    - Conference Organization 3/3, 1981; F-57-15-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 57-104)
    - Conference Mailing List - Correspondence and Lists, 1980 - 1981; F-57-15-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 57-104)
    - Conference Papers 1/2, 1981; F-57-15-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 57-104)
    - Conference Papers 2/2, 1981; F-57-15-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 57-104)
  - Foreign Investment Review Act, 1974 - 1985; F-57-15-2; 24 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of records relating to the federal Foreign Investment Review Act (FIRA) and on the ownership changes of particular publishing companies, control within the North American publishing industry, and the public response to the threatened closure of Macmillan Publishing in 1980. Included are legislation, correspondence, annual and other reports, clippings, newsletters, memoranda and news releases.
    The FIRA files are ordered chronologically; the publishing house files are arranged alphabetically.
    - Foreign Ownership, 1974 - 1978; F-57-15-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Act, 1974 - 1979; F-57-15-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Agency, 1977 - 1982; F-57-15-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Act, 1978 - 1979; F-57-15-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Act, 1979; F-57-15-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Act, 1980 - 1981; F-57-15-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Act, 1980 - 1984; F-57-15-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Act - Quarterly Reports, 1979 - 1981; F-57-15-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Foreign Investment Review Act - Quarterly Reports, 1981 - 1982; F-57-15-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - American Society for Metals, 1985; F-57-15-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - B.P.A.L, 1978; F-57-15-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Collier MacMillan, 1976 - 1979; F-57-15-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Dow Jones / Irwin Dorsey, 1976 - 1982; F-57-15-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Les Editions Julienne, 1978; F-57-15-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Fawcett and Dell, 1977 - 1980; F-57-15-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 57-105)
    - Gage, 1977 - 1980; F-57-15-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Globe / Modern, 1975 - 1984; F-57-15-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Guiness Book of Records, 1975; F-57-15-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 1974; F-57-15-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Lippincott, 1978 - 1980; F-57-15-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Longman, 1978 - 1979; F-57-15-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - McGraw-Hill Ryerson, 1978 - 1979; F-57-15-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - MacMillan, 1980; F-57-15-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - MacMillan - NAL, 1977 - 1983; F-57-15-2-0-24 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Random House, 1976 - 1982; F-57-15-2-0-25 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Rizzoli, 1976; F-57-15-2-0-26 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Toys R US, 1984; F-57-15-2-0-27 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - United Parcel Service, 1977; F-57-15-2-0-28 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - Whitman Golden, 1979 - 1982; F-57-15-2-0-29 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
    - World Book - Childcraft, 1978 - 1980; F-57-15-2-0-30 (Archival box - standard 57-106)
  - Fulfillment Working Group papers, 1975 - 1978; F-57-15-3; 9 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of records of the Fulfillment Working Group. Chaired by James Lorimer, the group researched the viability of organizing a co-operative publishers warehouse. The group commissioned studies from Rien Hennephof and Haskin and Sells and drew up a proposal which was never implemented. Included are correspondence, papers, surveys, and proposals.
    - Chronlogical Files, 1976 - 1977; F-57-15-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Correspondence: Mike Preston, 1976 - 1977; F-57-15-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Memoranda, Papers, 1975 - 1976; F-57-15-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Memoranda, Papers, 1976 - 1978; F-57-15-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Questionnaire Replies - Fulfilment Interest, 1976; F-57-15-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Questionnaire Replies - Cost Survey, 1976; F-57-15-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Questionnaire Replies - Fulfilment Support, 1977; F-57-15-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Consultants Proposals, 1976; F-57-15-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Reports - Fulfilment Project, 1976 - 1977; F-57-15-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
  - Policy files, 1972 - 1982; F-57-15-4; 19 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of records relating to the subject of government policy in the fields of copyright, foreign investment, co-publishing, cultural industries and book tariffs. Also documented is the Tariff Monitoring Work Group, a joint government/industry endeavour under the auspices of the Book and Periodical Development Council set up to monitor the effects of zero-rating the import tariff on books. Included are articles, briefs, minutes and papers.
    The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Canadian Copyright, R.J. Roberts, 1979; F-57-15-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Copyright Act Import Provisions, A.J. Blonqvist, 1979; F-57-15-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Copyright Remedies, Consumer and Corporate Affairs, Canada, 1981; F-57-15-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 57-107)
    - Federal Co-publishing Policy, 1975 - 1979; F-57-15-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Foreign Investment Review, R.A. Donaldson, 1982; F-57-15-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Liberals Cultural Policy, 1979 - 1980; F-57-15-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - N.D.P. Publishing Policy, 1979 - 1980; F-57-15-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Net Book Agreement, 1979; F-57-15-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Policy Briefs: IPA/ACP, BPDC, 1972 - 1975; F-57-15-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff Concessions - GATT, 1980; F-57-15-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff and Markups, 1979; F-57-15-4-0-11 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff - Monitoring Work Group Minutes, 1979 - 1980; F-57-15-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff - Monitoring Work Group Papers, 1980 - 1982; F-57-15-4-0-13 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff on Paper, 1979; F-57-15-4-0-14 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff - ACP Press Release, 1979; F-57-15-4-0-15 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff - IPA Policy Papers, 1974 - 1975; F-57-15-4-0-16 (Archival box - standard 57-108)
    - Tariff - Statistical Tables on Zero Rating, 1981; F-57-15-4-0-17 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - Tariff - Study of the Impact of Florence Agreement, 1977; F-57-15-4-0-18 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
  - Statistics, 1973 - 1983; F-57-15-5; 22 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of records relating to the IPA/ACP work with Statistics Canada to improve and refine the federal governments' annual statistics on the book publishing industry. Included are a draft and final versions of the survey questionnaires, survey booklets, draft reports, statistical tables, correspondence and clippings.
    - 1972 Data (no source), 1973; F-57-15-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - 1973 Data, article, 1976; F-57-15-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - Statistics Canada - Book Publishing Survey, 1975 - 1976; F-57-15-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - Statistics Canada - Analysis of Survey, 1975 - 1976; F-57-15-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - 1975 Data - Working File: Paul Audley, 1975 - 1977; F-57-15-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - 1975 Data - ACP report, 1978; F-57-15-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - 1976 Data - Statistics Canada, 1976 - 1978; F-57-15-5-0-7 (Archival box - standard 57-109)
    - 1977 Data - Statistics Canada, 1977 - 1980; F-57-15-5-0-8 (Archival box - standard 57-110)
    - Statistics Canada - 1975-1977 - Financial Analysis, 1975 - 1981; F-57-15-5-0-9 (Archival box - standard 57-110)
    - Statistics Canada - 1975-1977 - Financial Analysi, 1975 - 1979; F-57-15-5-0-10 (Archival box - standard 57-110)
    - 1978 Data - Statistics Canada - Correspondence, clippings, survey booklets, drafts, 1977 - 1980; F-57-15-5-0-11 (Archival box - standard 57-110)
    - Statistics Canada Surveys - Questionnaires, correspondence, 1979 - 1983; F-57-15-5-0-12 (Archival box - standard 57-110)
- Publications, 1972 - 1985; F-57-16; 25 cm of textual records
  Series consists of brochures, handbooks, catalogues, pamphlets and reports produced by the ACP or drawn from the ACP's collection. Included are IPA/ACP information brochures, handbooks and directories, Literary Press Group catalogues, reports taken from the Education Committee's collection of publications and a pamphlet celebrating the fifteenth anniversary of the House of Anansi.
  - IPA / ACP Brochures (mostly undated), 1972 - 1985; F-57-16-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 57-111)
  - ACP Members' Handbook, 1976 - 1977; F-57-16-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 57-111)
  - The Literary Press Group Catalogues, 1976 - 1979; F-57-16-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 57-111)
  - The Literary Press Group Catalogues, 1980 - 1983; F-57-16-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 57-111)
  - Needed: Canadian Textbooks pamphlet - Atlantic Institute of Education, 1975; F-57-16-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 57-112)
  - Canadian Content Survey, Philippe Cassidy, 1974; F-57-16-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 57-112)
  - The British Mission in Canada, Seminar Proceedings, 1978; F-57-16-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 57-112)
  - Canadian Learning Materials in Elementary and Secondary Education, ACP and CSTA, 1981; F-57-16-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 57-112)
  - Anansi at Fifteen: A Spider's Life, James Polk, 1982; F-57-16-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 57-112)